<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<schemalist gettext-domain="status-tray">
  <schema id="org.gnome.shell.extensions.status-tray" path="/org/gnome/shell/extensions/status-tray/">

    <key name="disabled-apps" type="as">
      <default>[]</default>
      <summary>Disabled apps</summary>
      <description>List of app IDs to hide from the tray. Apps in this list will not show tray icons even when running.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="icon-mode" type="s">
      <default>'symbolic'</default>
      <summary>Icon display mode</summary>
      <description>How to display tray icons. 'symbolic' converts icons to monochrome to match the panel style. 'original' shows the app's original colored icons.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="app-order" type="as">
      <default>[]</default>
      <summary>App order</summary>
      <description>Custom ordering of tray items by app ID. Apps not in this list appear in discovery order.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="icon-overrides" type="a{ss}">
      <default>{}</default>
      <summary>Icon overrides</summary>
      <description>Map of app IDs to custom icon names or file paths. When set, these override the app-provided icon.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="icon-effect-overrides" type="a{ss}">
      <default>{}</default>
      <summary>Per-app icon effect overrides</summary>
      <description>Map of app IDs to JSON-encoded effect parameters. Each value is a JSON object with: desaturation (0-1), brightness (-1 to 1), contrast (0-2), useTint (boolean), tintColor ([r,g,b] 0-1 each).</description>
    </key>

    <key name="icon-fallback-overrides" type="as">
      <default>[]</default>
      <summary>Fallback-only icon overrides</summary>
      <description>List of app IDs whose icon overrides are only used when the app sends a pixbuf or no icon.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="icon-lock-overrides" type="as">
      <default>[]</default>
      <summary>Locked icon overrides</summary>
      <description>List of app IDs whose icon overrides ignore app status icon changes. When locked, the chosen override stays in place regardless of NewIcon signals from the app.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="title-aliases" type="a{ss}">
      <default>{}</default>
      <summary>Display-name aliases for apps with unstable SNI Ids</summary>
      <description>Maps an app's display name to a stable appId used as the settings key. Opt-in per app via the "Match by App Name" switch in icon customization. Intended for apps (e.g. Karing) that randomize their SNI Id on every launch.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="overflow-enabled" type="b">
      <default>false</default>
      <summary>Enable panel overflow</summary>
      <description>When enabled, tray items beyond the inline limit collapse into a single overflow button at the rightmost end of the tray.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="overflow-inline-count" type="i">
      <default>3</default>
      <summary>Inline icon count</summary>
      <description>Number of tray items to show directly in the panel before overflowing into the overflow button's menu. Set to 0 to keep every tray item in the overflow menu. Range: 0-20.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="overflow-icon-style" type="s">
      <default>'dynamic'</default>
      <summary>Overflow icon style</summary>
      <description>How to render the overflow button in the panel. 'dynamic' previews up to four hidden tray icons; 'static' uses the bundled tray glyph.</description>
    </key>

  </schema>
</schemalist>
